A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
- Miscellaneous
  - Scrapbook containing typescript copies of letters from: Hugh Walpole, Louis Untermeyer, George Sterling, Kate Langley Bosher, Sinclair Lewis, H. L. Mencken, Ernest A. Boyd, Gilbert Cannan, Edward Hale Bierstadt, Joseph Hergesheimer, Wilson Follett, Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy& Pierre Troubetzkoy, Sidney Howard, Paul Jordan Smith, James Hopper, T. R. Smith, William Rose Benet and Ellis P. Oberholtzer to Guy Holt re: the attempted suppression of Jurgen. Also in scrapbook are various newspaper clippings re: James Branch Cabell and Jurgen, ca. 1919; Scrapbook
  - Transcripts of legal proceedings in People of the State of New York vs. Guy Holt, Robert M. McBride & Co.& Robert M. McBride in the case against Jurgen, 1920 Jan 14; Legal proceedings
  - Legal indictment against Guy Holt, Robert M. McBride & Co.& Robert M. McBride of "unlawfully possessing an indecent book" [ Jurgen ], [1920 Jan 14]; Indictment
  - John S. Summer, Agent for the Suppression of Vice, lists particular pages of Jurgen containing scenes of lewdness and obscenity, 1920 Jan 15; Legal proceedings, 2 p.
  - "In Re: A Certain Offensive Lewd Lascivious in Decent Book Called Jurgen " describing passages that have been called offensive, [1920 Jan 30]; Legal proceedings. 5 p.
  - Legal statement in support of Jurgen by defendant, 1920 Feb 5; Legal statements, 4 p.
  - Indictment, The People vs. Guy Holt& Robert M. McBride & Co., [1920] May 17; Indictment
  - Publication announcements of the Robert M. McBride & Co., 1920-1921; Printed material
  - News clipping, "Books of Yesteryear: Cabell in 1904" from N.Y. Tribune, 1922 May 7; Clipping
  - James Branch Cabell- autograph, n.d.; Autograph